<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section id="effects">
	<title>Transitions and Effects</title>
	<indexterm><primary>transitions</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>effects</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		The photos in a <application>PhotoPulse</application> show are displayed using a series of transitions and effects.
		A <guilabel>Transition</guilabel> defines how one photo transitions out from the
 		previous photo and into the next photo in the show.
		The transitions for two adjacent photos will overlap in time
 		(play simultaneously during the transition period).
		An <guilabel>Effect</guilabel> defines how an individual photo is displayed.
		Each photo has a beginning transition, an effect and an ending transition.
	</para>
	<para>
		For example, photo A has a falling leaves effect and a fade out ending transition.
		Photo B has a falling snowflake effect and a fade in beginning transition.
		In this case, photo A is displayed with the falling leaves effect until the transition period.
		At that time it begins to fade out while at the same time photo B
		begins to fade in while displaying the falling snowflake effect.
		When the transition period is over, photo A has faded to invisibility and photo B
		is now fully opaque and is continuing to display its falling snowflake effect.
	</para>
	<para>
		The <guilabel>Transitions In Tab</guilabel>,
		<guilabel>Effects Tab</guilabel> and <guilabel>Transitions Out Tab</guilabel>
		can be used to select the set of transitions and effects that will be chosen when creating a show.
		See <xref linkend="effects.tabs"/> for more information.
	</para>
	<para>
		You can preview the different transitions and effects
		<!-- One of these will be used, depending on website or help build.
			For the website, the previews are inserted inline below via the build process. -->
		<phrase condition="help"><ulink url="http://www.photopulse.com/help/UsersGuide.html#previews">here</ulink>.</phrase>
		<phrase condition="website"><ulink url="#previews">here</ulink>.</phrase>
	</para>
	<section id="effects.tabs">
		<title>Transitions and Effects Tabs</title>
		<para>
			The <guilabel>Transitions and Effects Tabs</guilabel> contain scrolling
			lists of checkboxes, enabling you to choose your preferred transitions
			and effects.
			The transitions and effects that are checked are the ones that will
			be used when automatically applying transitions and effects.
		</para>
		<para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry id="effects.TransitionsInTab"><term>Transitions In Tab</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Check the checkboxes of your preferred beginning transitions
							(the transition that plays as a new photo transitions onscreen).
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="effects.EffectsTab"><term>Effects Tab</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Check the checkboxes of your preferred effects
							(the effect plays the entire time the photo is onscreen).
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="effects.TransitionsOutTab"><term>Transitions Out Tab</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Check the checkboxes of your preferred ending transitions
							(the transition that plays as an existing photo transitions offscreen).
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>
	</section>
</section>