<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section userlevel="expert" id="expert">
	<title>Expert Mode</title>
	<indexterm><primary>Expert Mode</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		Expert Mode gives you more control over the show that is created.
		Instead of <application>PhotoPulse</application> randomly picking transitions and effects and
		setting the duration of each photo, Expert Mode allows you to fine tune these choices.
		To turn on Expert Mode, check the <guimenuitem>Expert Mode</guimenuitem>
		menu item checkbox in the <guimenu>View</guimenu> menu.
		When you enter Expert Mode, an Expert Panel
 		appears on the right in the <guilabel>Photos Tab</guilabel>.
		This panel can be resized by dragging the separator bar along its left edge.
	</para>
	<para>
		The Expert Panel allows you to change the beginning transition,
		effect and ending transition for each photo.
 		You can also set the durations of each of these, and the photos caption.
		Using the Expert Panel, you can also preview how a photo will look
		with its transitions and effect and view a larger size image of a photo.
	</para>
	<para>
		To use the Expert Panel, you must first select a photo in the thumbnail list.
		The Expert Panel will change to reflect the current settings for that photo.
		You can then use the controls described below in the Expert Panel to change the photos settings.
		If you select multiple photos in the thumbnail list at one time,
 		the Expert Panel can be used
		to change the settings for all selected photos at once.
		If all the photos selected have the same value for a setting,
 		then the control will display that value.
		If some photos have a different value, then the control will be blank.
		Either way, a new value can be entered in the control and it will change
		that setting for all selected photos to the entered value.
	</para>
	<para>
		In addition to the Expert Panel, there are two menu items in
		the <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menu that are useful in Expert Mode.
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry id="expert.RandomizeEffects"><term><guimenuitem>Randomize Effects</guimenuitem><indexterm><primary>randomize effects</primary></indexterm></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Chooses random transitions and effects for every photo in the show.
						Photos that are locked will not have their transitions or effect changed.
						After randomizing, you can then choose individual photos and change their transitions
						and effects to fine tune the show.
						The random transitions and effects are chosen from the set of selected
						transitions and effects on the <guilabel>Transitions In Tab</guilabel>,
						<guilabel>Effects Tab</guilabel> and <guilabel>Transitions Out Tab</guilabel>.
						See <xref linkend="effects.tabs"/> for more information.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry id="expert.RedistributeTime"><term><guimenuitem>Redistribute Time</guimenuitem><indexterm><primary>redistribute time</primary></indexterm></term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Modifies the effect timing of each unlocked photo to make
						the duration of the show match the duration of the MP3 soundtrack.
						So for example, you could modify the effect duration of the first
						and last photo in the show to be long, then lock those two photos
 						and choose <guimenuitem>Redistribute Time</guimenuitem> and the
						effect durations of the unlocked photos would be padded so that the total show
						duration matches the MP3 duration.
						If no photos are locked, then
						<guimenuitem>Redistribute Time</guimenuitem> will divide the MP3 duration
						equally among all your photos.
						If you do not have an MP3 loaded, then the total show duration is used.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</para>
	<section id="expert.panel">
		<title>Expert Panel</title>
		<indexterm><primary>Expert Panel</primary></indexterm>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<caption><para>Expert Panel</para></caption>
				<imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/expertPanel.png"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>

			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry id="expert.lock">
					<term>Lock<indexterm><primary>lock</primary></indexterm></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Selecting this checkbox will lock the photo.
							A locked photos transitions and effect and their durations cannot be changed unless it is first unlocked.
							A photo can be locked to prevent its transitions and effect from being changed
							when using the <xref linkend="expert.RandomizeEffects"/> command
 							and to prevent its durations from being changed when using the <xref linkend="expert.RedistributeTime"/> command.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="expert.viewPhoto">
					<term>
						View photo
						<inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/viewPhotoButton.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>
					</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the photo viewer dialog.
							This presents a larger view of the currently selected photo.
							It also has controls to step forwards and backwards through your photos,
							and to delete the current photo.
							This is useful when you have a number of similar photos and cannot distinguish
							them by their thumbnails.
							You can use the photo viewer to see the photos larger and delete the ones you don't want.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>
						Simple effect preview
						<inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/previewSimpleButton.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>
						<indexterm><primary>preview effect</primary></indexterm>
					</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays an animated Flash thumbnail preview of the currently selected photo and the
							following photo.
							This is a fast way to get a rough idea of how the effects and the transitions between
							the two photos will appear.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="expert.fullPreview">
					<term>
						Full effect preview
						<inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/previewThemeButton.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>
						<indexterm><primary>preview theme</primary></indexterm>
					</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							This is the same as the <guilabel>Simple effect preview</guilabel>,
							except the currently selected Theme will be applied to the preview.
							The preview will be at full size and with any captions and other Theme settings applied.
							See <xref linkend="themes"/> for more information.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="expert.caption"><term>Photo Caption<indexterm><primary>captions</primary></indexterm></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the text caption for the selected photo(s).
							Clicking the caption button drops down an editable text area where the caption
							can be entered or modified.
							When you have entered the caption, press <keycap>Esc</keycap>
							or click outside the text area to apply the caption text.
							Photo captions are displayed with their photo by some Themes.
							See <xref linkend="themes"/> for more information.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Transitions In</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the beginning transition and its duration in seconds for the selected photo(s).
						</para>
						<para>
							You can change the beginning transition by selecting from the scrolling dropdown list.
							The beginning transitions that you have unchecked on the
							<guilabel>Transitions In Tab</guilabel>
							(see <xref linkend="effects.TransitionsInTab"/>)
							will be displayed at the bottom of the list and greyed out,
							however you can still select them.
						</para>
						<para>
							You can change the beginning transition duration in seconds by typing a new
							value or using the up/down arrows to change the value.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="expert.effects"><term>Effects</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the effect and its duration in seconds for the selected photo(s).
						</para>
						<para>
							You can change the effect by selecting from the scrolling dropdown list.
							The effects that you have unchecked on the
							<guilabel>Effects Tab</guilabel>
							(see <xref linkend="effects.EffectsTab"/>)
							will be displayed at the bottom of the list and greyed out,
							however you can still select them.
						</para>
						<para>
							The <guibutton>Customize...</guibutton> button will open the
 							<guilabel>Pan &amp; Zoom Editor</guilabel> (see <xref linkend="panzoom"/>),
							allowing you to customize the effect on the selected photo.
							The dropdown effect list will display <emphasis><guilabel>Customized Effect</guilabel></emphasis>
							when the selected photo has had its effect customized.
						</para>
						<para>
							You can change the effect duration by typing a new
							value in seconds or using the up/down arrows to change the value.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Transitions Out</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the ending transition, its duration in seconds
							and its layer for the selected photo(s).
						</para>
						<para>
							You can change the ending transition by selecting from the scrolling dropdown list.
							The effects that you have unchecked on the
							<guilabel>Transitions Out Tab</guilabel>
							(see <xref linkend="effects.TransitionsOutTab"/>)
							will be displayed at the bottom of the list and greyed out,
							however you can still select them.
						</para>
						<para>
							You can change the ending transition layer by selecting from the dropdown list.
							Choosing <guilabel>Above next</guilabel> means that the selected photos ending
							transition will play on top of the following photos beginning transition.
							Choosing <guilabel>Below next</guilabel> means that the selected photos ending
							transition will play underneath the following photos beginning transition.
						</para>
						<para>
							You can change the ending transition duration by typing a new
							value in seconds or using the up/down arrows to change the value.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="expert.showDuration"><term>Show Duration<indexterm><primary>duration</primary><secondary>show</secondary></indexterm></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the total duration of all the photos in the show (minutes:seconds.hundredths).
							If this is less than the <guilabel>MP3 Duration</guilabel>, then the photos will
							finish playing first and the MP3 soundtrack will continue with no photos displayed.
							If this is greater than the <guilabel>MP3 Duration</guilabel>,
							then the MP3 soundtrack will finish first and the photos will continue to play silently.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>MP3 Duration<indexterm><primary>duration</primary><secondary>MP3</secondary></indexterm></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the total duration of the MP3 soundtrack, if any (minutes:seconds.hundredths).
							See the discussion of <guilabel>Show Duration</guilabel> for the duration relationship
							between show and MP3.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>

		&panzoom.xml;
	</section>
</section>


