<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section id="music">
	<title>Music</title>
	<para>
		You can add a single MP3 song or a sequence of songs (playlist) to your show.
		The music soundtrack plays as your photos are displayed during the show.
		If your show has a soundtrack, you can disable it using the <guilabel>Settings Tab</guilabel>,
 		see <xref linkend="settings.mp3"/> for more information.
	</para>
	<section>
		<title>Adding Music</title>
		<indexterm><primary>music</primary><secondary>adding</secondary></indexterm>
		<indexterm><primary>Music... button</primary></indexterm>
		<para>
			The <guibutton>Music...</guibutton> button and the
			<guimenu>File</guimenu>|<guimenuitem>Music...</guimenuitem>
			menu item both display the MP3 file chooser, allowing you to
			select MP3 music files to use as a soundtrack for your show.
		</para>
		<para>
			The MP3 file chooser has a <guilabel>Listen</guilabel> hyperlink
			which will play the currently selected MP3 file using your
			systems media player.
			This can be used to preview music files as you select one.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can only select a single file to use as the soundtrack.
			Each time you select a file using the MP3 file chooser,
			it replaces the current file with the new one.
			You can see the currently selected MP3 file in the tooltip displayed
			by hovering your mouse over the <guibutton>Music...</guibutton> button
			at the bottom of the main <application>PhotoPulse</application> window.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="music.playlist">
		<title>MP3 Playlist Editor</title>
		<indexterm><primary>music</primary><secondary>playlist</secondary></indexterm>
		<para>
			In addition to MP3 files, you can also choose MP3 playlist (M3U) files.
			An MP3 playlist is an ordered list of references to other MP3 files
			to play in sequence.
			This allows you to use multiple MP3 files for your soundtrack by
			building a playlist containing the MP3 files you want,
			and choosing the M3U playlist as the single music file for your show.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can create your own M3U file using the MP3 Playlist Editor.
			Choose <guimenuitem>Build MP3 Playlist...</guimenuitem> from the <guimenu>Tools</guimenu> menu
			to display the editor.
			If your current music file is an M3U file, then the editor will load it
			and allow you to edit the contents.
			Otherwise the editor will allow you to create a playlist from scratch.
			<mediaobject>
				<caption><para>MP3 Playlist Editor</para></caption>
				<imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/mp3Playlist.png"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry><term>MP3 File List</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the MP3 files currently in your playlist.
							The order the files are displayed is the order they will play back.
							Click on a filename to select it,
							Ctrl-Click and Shift-Click to select multiple files at one time.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Add...</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the MP3 file chooser allowing you to choose MP3 files to add
							to the playlist.
							You can select multiple files at once in the file chooser by using
							Ctrl-Click and Shift-Click.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Remove</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Removes the selected MP3 files from your playlist.
							This does not delete the files from your disk,
							it just excludes them from the playlist.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Move Up</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Moves the selected MP3 files up in the playlist.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Move Down</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Moves the selected MP3 files down in the playlist.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Load...</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays an M3U file chooser, allowing you to load a new M3U playlist to edit.
							The current playlist will be replaced by the new one loaded.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Save...</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays an M3U file chooser, allowing you to save the current playlist to an M3U file.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>OK</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Dismisses the playlist editor and makes the new M3U playlist file
							the new music soundtrack for your show.
							If you have not yet saved your playlist as an M3U file,
							you will first be prompted to save it.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>
	</section>
</section>