<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section id="overview">
	<title>Creating Shows</title>
	<para>
		The process of creating a <application>PhotoPulse</application> show is simple.
		<phrase userlevel="expert">
			To let <application>PhotoPulse</application> do the hard work,
			first check the <guimenu>View</guimenu> menu and
			make sure you are <emphasis>not</emphasis> currently in <guimenuitem>Expert Mode</guimenuitem>.
			When you are not in Expert Mode, <application>PhotoPulse</application> does most of the work for you,
			but you have less control over how the final show appears.
		</phrase>
	</para>
	<para>
		Use the <guibutton>Photos...</guibutton> button to open the photos
		to include in your show.
		If you want a music soundtrack in your show, use the <guibutton>Music...</guibutton>
		button to open an MP3 file.
		Finally, <guibutton>Create...</guibutton> will prompt you to
		choose the type of show to create and enter a filename for the show.
	</para>
	<para>
		If your show has an MP3 soundtrack, when you create a show <application>PhotoPulse</application> will automatically adjust the show
		so that your photos play the entire time the soundtrack is playing.
		It does this by repeating photos in your show if needed to "pad" out the show
		to fill the MP3 duration.
		It may also temporarily remove photos from the final show if there are too many
		photos to fit within a short MP3.
		You can adjust this behavior by changing the speed at which the show plays
		(the length of time each photo is displayed).
		See see <xref linkend="settings.speed"/>.
	</para>
	<para>
		Each time you create your show, <application>PhotoPulse</application> will choose a new random set of transitions
		and effects for each photo.
		It will choose transitions and effects from the set that you have selected
		on the <guilabel>Transitions and Effects Tabs</guilabel> (see <xref linkend="effects.tabs"/>).
	</para>
	<para>
		Each of these steps is covered in more detail in the following sections.
		<phrase userlevel="expert">
			The description above applies to shows created when not in Expert Mode.
			If you want more control over creating shows, you can turn on Expert Mode.
			See <xref linkend="expert"/> for more information.
		</phrase>
	</para>

	&photos.xml;
	&music.xml;
	&effects.xml;
	&create.xml;

</section>

