<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section userlevel="expert" id="panzoom">
	<title>Pan &amp; Zoom Editor</title>
	<indexterm><primary>Pan</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>Zoom</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>Rotate</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		The <guilabel>Pan &amp; Zoom Editor</guilabel> is opened using the
		<guibutton>Customize...</guibutton> button on the <guilabel>Expert Panel</guilabel>
		(see <xref linkend="expert.effects"/>).
		This editor is used to create a customized, documentary-style pan
 		and zoom (with rotation) animation sequence using your photo.
		You create a number of <emphasis>keyframes</emphasis>
		<indexterm><primary>keyframe</primary></indexterm>
		defining the important points in the animation sequence.
		Each keyframe occurs at a specific time in the animation,
		and specifies the position (pan), zoom (size) and rotation of the photo at that point in time.
		The position, zoom and rotation of the photo at each point in time between two keyframes
		is automatically computed for you
 		(using a process called <emphasis>interpolation</emphasis> or <emphasis>tweening</emphasis>).
 	</para>
	<para>
		<mediaobject>
			<caption><para>Pan &amp; Zoom Editor</para></caption>
			<imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/panzoomEditor.png"/></imageobject>
		</mediaobject>

		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Stage</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The stage displays the settings of the currently selected keyframe
						as applied to the photo. The shaded areas of the stage represent those
						areas that will not be visible in the final show.
						What you see in the unshaded (clear) area of the stage is what you will
						see in the final show.
						The shape of the unshaded area changes to match the shape of the current
						<link linkend="themes">theme</link> selected.
					</para>
					<para>
						The photo in the stage can be dragged with the mouse to change its position.
						The other controls to the right of the stage can also be used to change
						the position, size and rotation of the photo.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Keyframe Timeline</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The timeline represents each keyframe in the animation,
						and their relative positions in time.
						The first keyframe is always at time zero and cannot be moved.
						Subsequent keyframes can be dragged to change the time at which they appear.
						Clicking a keyframe selects it and changes the stage
						and other controls to reflect the settings for that keyframe.
					</para>
					<para>
						The portion of the timeline that is during the beginning and ending transitions
						is shaded a lighter gray.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guibutton>Add</guibutton> button adds a new keyframe immediately
						after the currently selected keyframe.
						The new keyframe will initially have the same settings as the previously
						selected keyframe.
						The <guibutton>Remove</guibutton> button removes the currently
						selected keyframe and selects the keyframe immediately before it.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Position</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>X</guilabel> and <guilabel>Y</guilabel> spinner controls
						can be used to adjust the position of the photo in the stage.
						They represent the coordinates of the center of the photo relative to the
						center of the stage (so X=0, Y=0 means the photo is centered in the stage).
						The photo can also be dragged in the <guilabel>Stage</guilabel>,
						the position spinners will update to reflect the current position.
					</para>
					<para>
						If you accidentally drag the photo off the stage so it is no longer visible,
						you can always enter 0 for each coordinate to recenter the photo.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Zoom</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The zoom (scale) slider changes the size of the photo in the stage.
						A zoom of zero is invisible, 100% is the full size of the original photo.
						As you drag the zoom slider, a rectangle with an X through the center is drawn
						on the stage to represent the size the photo will become once you release the slider.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Rotation</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The rotation thumbwheel changes the rotation of the photo in the stage.
						Drag (spin) it to the left to rotate counter-clockwise,
						drag (spin) it to the right to rotate clockwise.
						The current rotation in degrees is displayed above the thumbwheel.
					</para>
					<para>
						A rotation of 0 degrees is unrotated. 90 degrees is flipped clockwise,
						-90 degrees is flipped counterclockwise.
						180 degrees is upside down, rotated clockwise.
						-180 degrees is upside down, rotated counterclockwise.
						360 degrees is one full clockwise rotation, so the photo appears unrotated in the stage.
						-360 degrees is one full counter-clockwise rotation, so the photo appears unrotated in the stage.
					</para>
					<para>
						Rotation is cumulative, so if one keyframe has a rotation of 0 degrees and the next
						is 720 degrees, then even though the photo appears unrotated in both keyframes,
						when the animation is played back the photo will spin through two complete clockwise
 						revolutions between the two keyframes.
					</para>
					<para>
						The button to the left of the thumbwheel sets the rotation to -90 degrees (flipped left).
						The button to the right sets the rotation to 90 degrees (flipped right).
						The button below the thumbwheel sets the rotation back to 0 degrees (unrotated).
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Smoothing</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Smoothing applies to a keyframe when the position of the photo in the keyframe
						changes from the previous and next keyframe.
						If the position changes, and <guilabel>Smoothing</guilabel> is checked,
						then the path that the photo takes through the current keyframe will be on a curve.
						If it is not checked, the path will be angular.
						Smoothing applies only if the keyframe has a keyframe before and after it.
						It does not have any effect on the first and last keyframes.
					</para>
					<para>
						Selecting <guilabel>Smoothing</guilabel> results in a smoother, more fluid animation
						when positions are changing between keyframes.
						However, sometimes when you need tighter control over the motion a photo takes,
						you may want to uncheck <guilabel>Smoothing</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Easing</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Easing slows the speed of the animation as it passes through the keyframe.
						When <guilabel>Easing</guilabel> is checked, the animation gradually slows as it enters
						and leaves the keyframe, resulting in a "lingering" effect.
 						When it is not checked, the animation speed is constant through the keyframe.
					</para>
					<para>
						Whereas <guilabel>Smoothing</guilabel> only applies to changes in position,
						<guilabel>Easing</guilabel> applies to all aspects of the animation
						(position, size and rotation). Checking <guilabel>Smoothing</guilabel> is useful,
						for example, when you want to zoom in on a portion of a photo, linger momentarily,
						then move on in the animation.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Preview</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Displays a preview of the current animation.
						The preview includes the beginning and ending transitions and theme.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	</para>
</section>