<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section id="photos">
	<title>Photos</title>
	<para>
		The <guilabel>Photos Tab</guilabel> displays thumbnail images of all the photos
		in your show.
		You can add and remove photos from your show, and change the order in which your photos
		are displayed during your show.
		<phrase userlevel="expert">
 			When you are in Expert Mode, the Expert Panel is also displayed in
			the <guilabel>Photos Tab</guilabel>.
			This panel provides additional settings you can apply to selected photos.
 			See <xref linkend="expert.panel"/> for more information.
 		</phrase>
	</para>
	<section id="photos.adding">
		<title>Adding Photos</title>
		<indexterm><primary>photos</primary><secondary>adding</secondary></indexterm>
		<indexterm><primary>Photos... button</primary></indexterm>
		<para>
			The <guibutton>Photos...</guibutton> button and the
			<guimenuitem>Photos...</guimenuitem> menu item in the <guimenu>File</guimenu> menu
			both display the Photo file chooser, allowing you to
			select photos to include in your show.
			Each time you use the Photo file chooser, the photos you choose are added
			to the your show along with any existing photos.
			So you can choose photos from one folder and add them to the show,
			then use the Photo file chooser again to select additional photos from a different folder.
		</para>
		<para>
			Thumbnails of the photos you open are displayed in the <guilabel>Photos Tab</guilabel>.
			The order in which the thumbnails are displayed is the order in which the photos
			will play back during the show.
			You can delete photos from your show and change their order using the <guilabel>Photos Tab</guilabel>.
		</para>
		<para>
			<mediaobject>
				<caption><para>Photo Chooser</para></caption>
				<imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/photoChooser.png"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry><term>Photo File List</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Displays the photo image files and folders in the current folder.
							Click on a filename to select it,
							Ctrl-Click and Shift-Click to select multiple files at one time.
							Click <guibutton>Open</guibutton> when you have selected the photos you want.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Open All</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Opens all photo files in the current directory.
							This is a shortcut to avoid selecting each file individually.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Preview</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							When this checkbox is checked, a thumbnail of
							the currently selected photo file will be displayed.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Files of Type</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <guimenuitem>Image</guimenuitem> to display image files.
 							Select <guimenuitem>Flash file</guimenuitem> to display Macromedia Flash files.
 							Flash animations can be loaded into a show and treated like a photo.
							The <guibutton>Preview</guibutton> thumbnail is disabled for Flash files.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Selecting Photos</title>
		<indexterm><primary>photos</primary><secondary>selecting</secondary></indexterm>
		<para>
			You can select a single photo by clicking on it.
			Hold the <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> key while clicking additional photo thumbnails to select multiple photos.
			You can select a range of photos.
 			Click to select the first photo in the range,
 			then hold the <keycap>Shift</keycap> key and click the last photo in the range.
			All photos in between the first and last photo will be selected.
			In the <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menu, use <guimenuitem>Select All</guimenuitem> to select all photos,
			and <guimenuitem>Deselect All</guimenuitem> to deselect all photos.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Manipulating Photos</title>
		<indexterm><primary>photos</primary><secondary>manipulating</secondary></indexterm>
		<para>
			You can change the ordering of photos by dragging them.
			Select the photos you want to move, then drag them to their new position
			and release the mouse button to move them there.
			As you drag the selected photos, a black insertion cursor will be drawn between photos
			to show you where the photos will be inserted when you drop them.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can duplicate photos by copying and pasting.
			Select the photos you want to copy and choose <guimenuitem>Copy</guimenuitem> from
			the <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menu.
			Then select the photo after which you want to place the duplicated photos
			and choose <guimenuitem>Paste</guimenuitem>.
			Copies of the selected photos will be inserted.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can remove photos from your show by selecting them and choosing
			<guimenuitem>Delete</guimenuitem> from the <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menu.
			You can also use <guimenuitem>Cut</guimenuitem> to remove photos,
			cut photos can then be pasted back into the show using <guimenuitem>Paste</guimenuitem>.
		</para>
		<para>
			Add new photos to your show using the <guibutton>Photos...</guibutton> button.
			See <xref linkend="photos.adding"/> for more information.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="photos.viewer">
		<title>Viewing Photos</title>
		<indexterm><primary>photos</primary><secondary>viewing</secondary></indexterm>
		<para>
			Double clicking on a thumbnail will display that photo in the <guilabel>Photo Viewer</guilabel>.
			This presents the photo in a larger size, allowing you to see more detail.
			While in the viewer you can step through the photos in your
			show using the viewer buttons. You can also delete the currently viewed photo from within the viewer.
			<phrase userlevel="expert">
				When in Expert Mode, you can also display the viewer using the <guilabel>View photo</guilabel>
				button in the Expert Panel.
				See <xref linkend="expert.viewPhoto"/> for more information.
			</phrase>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="photos.tooltips">
		<title>Photo Tooltips</title>
		<indexterm><primary>photos</primary><secondary>tooltips</secondary></indexterm>
		<para>
			Pausing your mouse over a photo thumbnail (without clicking) will cause a tooltip to be
 			displayed near the upper right corner of the window.
			<mediaobject>
				<caption><para>Photo Tooltip</para></caption>
				<imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/photoTooltip.png"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			The tooltip contains the photo filename followed by the time at which the photo will
			be displayed in your show in parenthesis (minutes:seconds.hundredths).
			Below that, the beginning transition, effect and ending transition names are displayed.
			The ending transition is followed by the ending transition layer in parenthesis.
		</para>
	</section>
</section>