<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section userlevel="expert" id="projects">
	<title>Projects</title>
	<indexterm><primary>projects</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		The photos, music soundtrack, transition and effect selections and other settings
 		that make up a show can be saved in a <application>PhotoPulse</application> project file.
		You can reopen the project later and continue working on it,
 		adding a few more photos or changing the music and other settings.
		If you open and modify a project, you can then save your changes replacing
		the existing project file, or save as a new project file without changing the original.
		See <xref linkend="menu.File"/> for more information on project related menu items.
	</para>
	<para>
		The project file does not actually store your photos and MP3,
		it references the original photo and MP3 files on your disk - only the file names are stored in the project.
		If you move the photos or MP3,
 		then when you open the project file later it will not be able to locate those files.
		If you load photos from a CDROM directly into a <application>PhotoPulse</application> show, then when you reopen that project
		you will need to have the CDROM inserted.
		Because of this, it is usually better to copy the photos from the CDROM onto your hard disk
		and load them into <application>PhotoPulse</application> from there.
	</para>
	<para>
		A good way to organize the files for a <application>PhotoPulse</application> project is like this:
<programlisting>
+ Birthday Show/
  |
  + Birthday Show.ppp
  + photos/
    |---photo1.jpg
    |---photo2.jpg
    |---[...]
    |---photoN.jpg
  + music/
    |---song.mp3
</programlisting>
		This way the project file and the photos and MP3 it references are all contained within the
		same folder (<filename>Birthday Show</filename>).
		This folder can then be renamed or moved without breaking the link between the project
		file and the photos it references.
	</para>
</section>