<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section id="themes">
	<title>Themes</title>
	<indexterm><primary>themes</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>skins</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		<application>PhotoPulse</application> themes define how a show looks when it plays back.
		The theme defines the size of the show (width X height),
		additional decorations such as a backdrop image or photo frame borders,
		and the position and style of any photo captions in the show
 		<phrase userlevel="expert">(see <xref linkend="expert.caption"/>)</phrase>.
	</para>
	<para userlevel="expert">
		You can preview a theme using the <guilabel>Full effect preview</guilabel> button
		in the Expert Panel.
 		See <xref linkend="expert.fullPreview"/> for more information.
	</para>
	<section>
		<title>Theme Chooser</title>
		<para>
			To select a theme for your show, click the <guibutton>Custom...</guibutton> button
			on the <guilabel>Settings Tab</guilabel> (see <xref linkend="settings.theme"/>).
			This will display the Theme Chooser.
			<mediaobject>
				<caption><para>Theme Chooser</para></caption>
				<imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/themeChooser.png"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry><term>Theme</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Lists the available themes installed on your system.
							Selecting a theme in this list will display a description of the theme
							and will display a list of available photo sizes for this theme in the
							<guilabel>Photo size</guilabel> list.
						</para>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>None</guilabel> theme is always available in the <guilabel>Theme</guilabel> list.
							It is a plain theme with no decorations, but it contains a variety of photo sizes for
 							common photo orientations and aspect ratios.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Photo size<indexterm><primary>size</primary></indexterm></term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Lists the available photo sizes for the selected theme.
							This is the size your photos will be displayed at - the actual show
							size itself might be larger due to theme decorations.
							The photo sizes that are recommended for the photos in your show
							are displayed normally. Photo sizes that are not a good match for your photos
							are displayed greyed out. These sizes can still be selected and used.
						</para>
						<para>
							When the <guilabel>None</guilabel> theme is selected, the photo sizes include
							an additional special size <guilabel>Custom size...</guilabel>.
							When this is selected, two additional controls appear allowing you
							to set a custom <guilabel>Width</guilabel> and <guilabel>Height</guilabel>
							for your skin.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry id="themes.description"><term>Description</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							When a theme is selected, a description of the theme appears in the panel
							below the theme list.
							This description may also include a thumbnail image of the theme decorations.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Backdrop Theme</title>
		<para>
			You can use your own photos to create a backdrop theme.
			A backdrop theme is a background image that your show plays in front of.
			To create a backdrop theme, create a single image that is the size you want
			your show to be. Place this image in the <application>PhotoPulse</application> <filename>skins</filename> folder.
			This folder is in the <application>PhotoPulse</application> installation directory
 			(e.g. <filename>C:\Program Files\<application>PhotoPulse</application>\skins</filename>).
			Restart <application>PhotoPulse</application> and your backdrop image name will appear in the theme list
			where you can select it as the theme for your show.
		</para>
	</section>

	&themes-advanced.xml;
</section>


