<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- ***** BEGIN LICENSE BLOCK *****
   - Version: MPL 1.1
   -
   - The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License Version
   - 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   - the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
   - http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
   -
   - Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" basis,
   - WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License
   - for the specific language governing rights and limitations under the
   - License.
   -
   - The Original Code is Photica Photopulse.
   -
   - The Initial Developer of the Original Code is
   - Photica Inc.
   - Portions created by the Initial Developer are Copyright (C) 2003
   - the Initial Developer. All Rights Reserved.
   -
   - Contributor(s):
   - Andrew Wason, Mike Mills
   - info@photica.com
   -
   - ***** END LICENSE BLOCK ***** -->

<section id="upload">
	<title>Uploading</title>
	<indexterm><primary>uploading</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>FTP</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>hosting</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>publishing</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		<application>PhotoPulse</application> makes it easy to publish web page (HTML) shows you create to a web site.
		After you have uploaded a show, you can send the URL to your show to other people so they can view it.
		Before you can upload a show, you need to configure your Upload Settings,
		see <xref linkend="upload.settings"/> for more information.
	</para>
	<section>
		<title>Choosing a Show</title>
		<para>
			To upload a show, use <guimenuitem>Upload Show...</guimenuitem> in the <guimenu>Tools</guimenu> menu
			(see <xref linkend="menu.Tools"/>).
			If you have not already configured your Upload Settings, you will be prompted to before you can upload.
			Next, you will be presented with the upload file chooser.
			Use this to choose the HTML show you wish to upload.
			You should select the HTML filename, the corresponding folder of associated files
			will also automatically be uploaded (e.g. choose <filename>MyShow.htm</filename>
			and folder <filename>MyShow_files</filename> will also be uploaded).
			You must create your shows in HTML format to upload them to a web site
			(see <xref linkend="create.showType"/>).
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>After Uploading</title>
		<para>
			While your show is uploading, a progress bar dialog will be displayed.
			You can move this aside and continue working with <application>PhotoPulse</application>.
			You can even upload multiple shows at the same time (each upload will have its own progress dialog).
			After the show has successfully uploaded, the dialog will change to display the URL of your uploaded show
 			if available.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can use the <guibutton>Copy</guibutton> tool button to copy the URL to the clipboard
			for pasting into an email message or other document.
			You can use the <guibutton>View Show</guibutton> button to view the uploaded show in your web browser.
			You can use the <guibutton>Manage Show</guibutton> button to go to the online file management
			area of your hosting provider in your web browser.
			These buttons will be disabled if your hosting provider does not provide this functionality.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="upload.settings">
		<title>Upload Settings</title>
		<para>
			<application>PhotoPulse</application> uses FTP (File Transfer Protocol) to upload your show to a web site.
			Check with your web site hosting provider to make sure they support FTP uploads.
			The Upload Settings dialog allows you to choose from a preconfigured hosting provider,
			or supply your own custom settings for any provider that supports FTP.
			Display the Upload Settings dialog using <guimenuitem>Upload Settings...</guimenuitem>
			in the <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menu (see <xref linkend="menu.Edit"/>).
			<mediaobject>
				<caption><para>Upload Settings</para></caption>
				<imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/uploadSettings.png"/></imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry><term>Login</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Enter your login or username for the FTP server.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Password</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Enter your password for the FTP server.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Save</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Check this box if you want <application>PhotoPulse</application> to remember your <guilabel>Password</guilabel>.
							If you leave this unchecked, you will be prompted to enter it each time you upload a show.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Hosting Provider</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Choose your hosting provider from the dropdown list.
							If your provider is not in the list, choose <guilabel>Custom</guilabel>
							and fill out the <guilabel>Custom Settings</guilabel> form.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Signup...</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Click this button to go to the website of the selected <guilabel>Hosting Provider</guilabel>
							to get information on how to sign up for an FTP account.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry><term>Custom Settings</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							This form will appear if you choose <guilabel>Custom</guilabel>
							from the <guilabel>Hosting Provider</guilabel> menu.

							<variablelist>
								<varlistentry><term>FTP server</term>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											Enter the hostname of your hosting providers FTP server.
										</para>
									</listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								<varlistentry><term>Port</term>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											Enter the FTP port, this will almost always be the default port 21.
										</para>
									</listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								<varlistentry><term>Server directory</term>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											If you want to upload shows into a subdirectory on the server,
											enter the directory path here.
											This directory will be created if it doesn't already exist.
										</para>
									</listitem>
								</varlistentry>
								<varlistentry><term>URL</term>
									<listitem>
										<para>
											Enter the HTTP URL that maps to the <guilabel>Server directory</guilabel>
											you entered above (or the FTP root if you did not enter a directory).
											This is the base URL you would enter in your web browser to access
											files you uploaded using FTP.
										</para>
									</listitem>
								</varlistentry>
							</variablelist>
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</para>
	</section>
</section>
